All right. How's everyone?
>> Good. How are you?
>> Let's get this show going. Um,
>> yeah. Questions.
>> Mickey made some acknowledgments that
there's some form of rebuilding mode or,
you know, restocking mode or whatever
the right term is for that in the last
year or two. Does that change your
philosophy on on on the aggressiveness
of trading up that that you've obvious?
>> No, not really. or the belief that more
picks is is needed or better or anything
like that?
>> No, I don't I don't think it it does. Um
we're going to approach this the same
way like and look, I say this every
year. We're not opposed to backing up if
it makes sense to us, but um it had made
sense to us the last few years.
>> There's been a talk of, you know, arm
length for uh you know, defensive
lineman, especially a guy like Ruben
Bane. when you, you know, analyze
defensive lineman, how much does that
kind of play a role into things and and
is there, you know, certain
circumstances where a player's tape
could, you know, overmatch any, you
know, quote unquote shortarms?
>> Yeah, I I think I think what, you know,
how the guy plays
always overrides everything. So, let's
let's, you know, start with that. Um,
but I do think this we've got a lot of
data um that tells us what plays in the
NFL. This isn't exclusive to um the
defensive line. It's all the positions.
We know what plays in the NFL. And we
have some some measurements that that
that
we can look at and say, "Man, that's an
outlier."
We're not looking for outliers. You
know, I say this to our guys. I've said
this over the years. If we are looking
for exceptions, then we're not going to
be here very long because exceptions are
exceptions. So, we're not looking for
exceptions, but we recognize that there
are exceptions. And so, if someone has
uh some traits that don't match what
plays in the NFL, then we better have
some other things that tell us that he
can overcome that. And so, um
yeah, that's my answer to that.
You standing at number eight in this
year's drafts. How much do you like this
position in the draft and how ideal is
it for this particular class?
>> Well, I don't like it because it means
that last year didn't go very well. So,
um you don't want to be picking in the
top 10, but once you know you get to the
draft and you look at the quality of the
players that exist, um yeah, you get
excited about I know we're going to get
a really good player at at pick eight.
Um, so you get excited about that. A guy
that can have an impact on your team.
>> Yeah. How do you guys like define the
unknowns that you can't maybe see on
film? Like a guy that you think might be
able to rush and pass it, but he's only
maybe has like 20 snaps of it or someone
you think might be able to drop back,
but hasn't done a whole lot of it.
>> Um, well, I think that gets back to
traits versus, you know, what you've
actually seen. And and look, this is
where sometimes the off season comes
into play in terms of the workouts, the
the the measurables, you know, the
things that tell you, yeah, a guy can do
something that maybe he hasn't been
asked to do yet.
>> Um,
and there's it's a balance, right? It's
a balance.
>> Where do you look at I guess your
thought process is you talked about the
exceptions picking in the top 10. You
don't do that that often. Are you more
prone to be we follow certain guidelines
in the top 10, maybe we could be a
little bit more exceptions at 28 than we
could at 8.
>> Yeah, I think you're I think for us,
we're probably a little more risk
averse. Um,
you know, when we when we make a pick
there, we want to have a lot of the
questions answered
uh about a player.
You don't want to pick a player that you
have a ton of questions about and you're
just you know banking on on uh you know
the unknown. Um
so I I think as you go farther back in
the draft you're a little more willing
to take a chance on someone. Um, but I
think in, you know, when you're in the
top 10 or top 12, whatever the number
is, you want to, uh, pick players that
you have, um, as little doubt as
possible that they're going to be
successful.
>> Does the timer going from 10 minutes to
8 minutes in the first round change like
the leg work you have to do on trades
and stuff ahead of the draft?
>> No, I I don't really I mean, I don't
know yet. I mean, we went from 15 to 10
at one point, and I didn't feel like
that had a big impact. Um,
I I don't think it will, but we'll see.
Um,
>> yeah, we'll see what happens.
>> A couple positions
>> that make this trap a little deeper. Um,
you know, I I don't know that I can say
that because deeper than what I mean,
you know, last year or the year before
or, you know, obviously there's fewer
quarterbacks being talked about in the
first round, so that changes the dynamic
a little bit, but
you know, and and I I hear sometimes,
you know, ah, this isn't a very deep
draft. I seem like I hear that every
year from different people and I kind of
feel like that's a little bit of an
excuse that if the draft doesn't go
well. Um I think there's good players in
every draft. I think there's guys that
are going to be Pro Bowl type players
and it's our job to identify them and
then hopefully we have an opportunity to
take them.
>> Mickey, you had uh your staff a lot of
your staff at Sydney Bowl. Joel Tom is
coach.
>> Yeah.
>> Um did you feel like you had a head
start on everybody else? Yeah, I think I
think it's uh uh look, we did have a lot
of coaches uh at the Senior Bowl and at
the East West game and and uh look,
that's development opportunity for those
coaches,
but it's a a great opportunity for us to
um you know, get get more information on
players that are going to be prominent
in this draft. And uh so that was really
good for us.
>> Speaking of things you probably hear
every year, uh a lot of people think
next year's draft class is really
stacked. Do you try to have a beat on
that when you're value?
>> No, I think it just changes and stuff
like that.
>> Um, not really. Uh, I mean, I'll ask
that question now and then of Jeff and
say, "Hey, what does next year look like
in terms of a position or or overall,
but I don't know that it's a it's a u
it's not that prominent in terms of when
we're we're making those discussions
just because things change so much over
the course of uh uh the college season.
M on the opposite side of that. Um the
class you had last year, immediate
impact guys, not as impactful as like
2017 or '06, but the fact that you had a
class with so much immediate impact and
got your quarterback. How does that
alter and make you want to have a proper
class to follow them up this year?
>> Yeah, I mean I I don't think it changes
anything. We always want to have a great
draft class. Um,
you know, I thought it was great for our
scouts and and Jeff and and his uh
people to get recognized for for last
year's success. Um,
but it doesn't have any impact on what
we're doing this year.
>> Yesterday, um, Tyler Shuck talked about
like how he's been evaluating receivers
like how much input do you all have or
like how involved is he? Yeah, I mean,
look, we'll we'll ask any of our players
that have a crossover with someone in
this draft, you know, and it's always
the young guys that played with someone.
If they've played with someone, we talk
to them about about, hey, what kind of
guy is he, you know, what how did how
did he, you know, learn? How did he uh
practice? You know, so we ask questions
of all our guys. It wasn't just Tyler.
Um,
you know, it's everybody on our team
that has a crossover with a player
that's in this draft that we may have um
an interest in in. How many scenarios do
you guys prepare for? Like what's your
like you know
>> how many mock drafts do we do?
>> Yeah. And then
>> like a hundred
>> when there when there's new like trade
rumors does do you go back and then
start looking through different
scenarios and how things might
>> Yeah. A little bit. Um and look here's
one great thing about the technology
now. We can just push a button and do
mock drafts. We don't have to, you know,
bring all of our scouts in a room and
assign them teams and then they make the
pick. you know, we have this technology
that allows us to uh to do these mock
drafts and and we do a lot of them. We
do um and so there's a lot of different
scenarios, particularly in the uh the
mid to later rounds, you know, because
that's that's where it gets a little I
don't want to say dicey, but that's
probably the only word I can think of um
as to what may happen.
>> Sean Pton's involvement in the draft was
pretty obvious and then and then it
seemed like Dennis Allen as well and had
been here for so long and collaborative.
What What was your philosophy and what
is your philosophy when you bring in
Kell Moore is new to the organization,
never been a head coach? Are you right
away like you know I want you to have as
strong a voice in this as anyone? Is it
more this year than last year? Like how
how
>> it was no different than when Sean first
got us got with us, right? He was a new
coach and I want the coaches involved. I
want them um I want to get their
perspective
and if we have differences um you know
between the personnel department and the
coaching staff, we got to we got to get
those ironed out before we we pick a
player out. You know, our goal is to all
be on the same page
in terms of the players that we bring in
here because that gives them and us the
best chance for them to be successful in
my opinion. when it comes to the
weighing thing
>> with what you all were able to
accomplish in in free agency. Is that
has that shifted anything with just like
your like how you're evaluating some
prospects? What what maybe you be
looking for more out of that? Especially
with a
>> don't pick I assume you want to be a
starter on the team.
>> Yeah, I I think it it look it certainly
affects us in terms of as we get later
in the draft, you know, you're trying
to, you know, fill slots on your roster.
I don't think it impacts us so much at
the top of the draft because, you know,
we're looking to take the best player
that's available to us when we pick. Um,
but as I've said before, generally
speaking, there's, you know, when you
when it's time to pick, you've got two
or three guys that you're choosing from
that are all in that same grade area,
and then you look at your roster and
say, "Hey, we need somebody at this
position more than the other one." So,
um, it definitely impacts it. Um
but it's not like the only impact
>> when it comes off of things that are
kind of premium and nonpremium positions
as people like to talk about times. Uh
slot corner is usually defined as
nonpremium. Is that different for you
all because of how Brandon Sy uses that
position in his defense?
>> Um
may maybe a little bit. I I wouldn't say
it's significantly different, but um
yeah, may but I'd say maybe a little
different. Yes. I mean, you have to pay
attention to the schemes you're running
and and and what you know, your coaching
staff values
um in terms of what they're trying to
get accomplished. So, yeah, it does have
some impact.
>> I noticed in Baton Rouge, uh you chat
with Monsour Delane, you were there for
his impressive pro day. um what did you
think of him and what kind of addition
do you think he would uh add to an NFL
team?
>> Yeah. Um look, I don't want to get into
a discussion about specific players, but
look, I I had a good talk with him. He's
impressive young man. Um I talked to him
about some of the things that he was
doing, you know, in the offseason and
and look, he he was great. He had great
answers and obviously a really good
player that's going to get taken high.
Going back to the draft philosophy now,
due to what you did in free agency, the
fact that you address so many needs, how
much has that freed you up to get best
player available instead of just best
player we need?
>> Yeah, I I think I've said this in prior
years, our goal in the offseason is
always to be in the position where we
can take, particularly at the top of the
draft, um the best player available. And
if we have to build a strength on our
team, then that's okay. Um, and so I
think this year probably as much as any
year, you know, we were able to do a few
things that allows us to do that.
>> You, uh, or I guess historically in the
league, you see trades up for
quarterbacks knowing that I assume
there's a quarterback going one and then
after that talks may not be about
quarterbacks. Has that been different
for you all or other teams or just
historically what you've seen because
people aren't moving up for the
quarterback?
Um, I don't know yet because I think
most of those calls start coming, you
know, today and tomorrow. Um, before the
draft, more so than than prior to.
Obviously, you know, we've heard from
some teams about teams that, hey, we
might want to move back here. Uh, a few
teams that that might want to move up,
not just in the first round, but but in
the second as well. um
you know it remains to be seen
you know how much of that activity
occurs but I wouldn't say it's a lot
different um than the past but again you
know picking in the top 10 is a
different it's a different uh you know
thing than picking in the middle or or
back half of the round. So you you get
fewer calls when you're back there as
opposed to when you're in the in the top
10.
>> Prospect that might be healed with an
injury during the pre-draft process.
>> Yeah, that I think that's difficult
sometimes because you you don't have as
much information so it creates more
questions, right? Um
but I think you know at the combine um
you know the medical people do a really
good job of assessing uh injuries. So,
we have a pretty good handle uh on on
guys that are hurt and what their
timelines are. Um but there may be some
unanswered questions in terms of some of
these measurables that that we value.
>> U there is a report that um Nasmire is
going to spend the draft with his son
until he gets drafted.
>> Yeah.
>> It is that a situation where he still
kind of works from afar and you'll call
to get his opinion or being the
situation's so rare, do you just kind of
let him unplug and
>> Yeah. No, listen, Doug. Doug's going to
be available to us. Um, and his input's
valuable. We've gotten most of that.
Look, all these questions that may come
up in the draft are mostly answered. And
so, um, you know, I don't anticipate
I don't anticipate a lot of questions
coming at, you know, when we're on the
clock or during the draft, but I know
Doug will be available and we value his
input.
attention that division pose what
they're doing.
>> Not much really. I mean, we note it
obviously, but we don't have any control
over that. So, um, you know, it is what
it is really.
>> How did the, uh, decision to let Doug
spend it with Derek kind of come about?
Was it idea your idea like that? How did
it
>> um, you know, I I don't know. That's a
good question. Um so but look I get that
you know
you know I advise him to spend it with
Garrett. It's a once in a lifetime
opportunity.
>> How do you think um the draft may impact
what you guys want to do with Alvin or
or guy like Cam
unsettled
>> guys? Yeah I I think that it could
impact it. Um you know we'll see what
happens and that goes both ways. that
may impact them uh from their
perspective as well as ours.
>> That it short.
>> Yeah. I don't we don't want to get into
any of that right now. You know, that's
we we'll do that after the draft. We got
a lot of questions that we got to get
answered over the next few few days
relative to our roster and and then
we'll go from there.
>> I I was going to ask about Cam Jordan
and Taesm Hill. Has there been any
resolution or they fall in the after the
draft? Yeah, you know, look, those those
are two-way questions, right? They have
things that they have to uh determine
and we do, too. So, um we'll see what
happens after the draft.
>> Think you would say the first round you
got two or three guys with the same kind
of grade
>> as the draft goes on, third, fourth,
fifth round, is that bullpen of players
grow a little bit?
>> Um yeah, I think it I think Well, you
hope it does. I mean, when we get to
the, you know, fifth and sixth round,
I'm hoping that we have four or five
guys that we can choose from, but
sometimes, you know, you get down there
and there's one guy that you that stands
out above all the rest. Um,
but you're hoping that you have four or
five because then, you know, the holes
that you have on your roster come into
play.
>> How much do you think last year's
success with the draft, I mean, it was
like one of the very years you didn't
trade at all. I Was it just having more
picks the marrier like or was there
something about the process that
>> um I I mean I don't know. I mean we made
some trades in 06 and that was a pretty
good draft and I don't remember if we
made trades in 17 or not but that was a
good draft too. So um
yeah I've said this before man if we
love somebody and and we feel like it's
necessary to make a move then we're
going to do that.
>> What do you think of uh the receiver
depth in this draft this year? Yeah, I'm
Look, I think it's good. It's it's it's
you know what I said before. There's
going to be good players in this draft
no matter what you think about that
depth. Um and it's up to us to get it
get them identified and then hopefully
you know we have the opportunity to take
those guys. Um but I I I do think
there's a lot of good receivers in this
draft. kind of I touched on this a
little bit earlier, but um are you ever
able to kind of get a sense before the
draft that that there is going to be a
lot of lot of moving pieces, trades
being made, etc. Like does that ever
kind of play out the way you envision it
doing?
>> Um,
you know, I don't know that I would say
it that way. I think there's there's
times when
um
yeah, it's a good question, but I don't
really think of it in those terms. You
know, I'm more focused on what we're
doing, not what everyone else is doing.
Um and I think the the higher up you
get, the more you're focused on what
you're doing, not what everyone else is
doing. And if an opportunity comes up,
then we look at it uh regardless of
whether that's an opportunity to move up
or move down. and then we'll make an
assessment that that makes sense for us
or not.
>> Those those conversations typically
start happening about 97.
>> Yeah, they're they're going to happen
over the next couple, you know, today
and tomorrow before the draft, you're
going to get a real sense and we already
have, you know, a couple of teams that
that we've talked to that um more than a
couple actually that have and and really
those conversations are just simply,
hey, we'd like to move down or we want
to move up. Um and then we'll have a
discussion in the next 24 hours about
okay what's the cost of that or what's
you know what are we getting for that
and and then you have you know you kind
of make this call in your mind about
yeah I do that for that and then we wait
and see what's available you know when
we're on the clock
>> yeah that was going to be
>> it's it's it's there's a lot of moving
parts in here
>> so it's sometimes contingent on like
okay if this happens and we're yeah
engaging re-engage in this conversation
>> I think It's almost always contingent
upon I mean because you're not trading
up for the spot, you're trading up for a
player. Um and so it's always okay is a
player available.
>> What's your read on on on the top seven
picks in this first year in this draft?
Do you think there's like six guys
that'll go in the top seven or do you
think this is one of those draft classes
where
>> who's the top seven? Well, that's what
I'm saying. I mean, do do you feel like
there's a consensus there or do you
think I mean, are your scenarios like it
could be pretty random
in that group this year based on what
teams do in front of you?
>> Yeah, it's a good question. Um, I
certainly don't think that all 32 teams
have the same seven guys listed from one
to seven. Um,
and I don't know what the other teams
are, you know, what their lists look
like. I know what our list looks like.
Um, so I don't I don't really pay
attention to that much. Um, it's a good
question. It just I don't have enough
information to answer it really.
>> I know you uh you joked about never
having traded back always trading up and
you joke about there could be
>> I've traded back
>> in the first round. Sorry. In the first
round. In the first round like
>> All right, I'll go with that.
>> But just hypothetically
>> can't deny the facts.
>> Sorry. Hypothetically, would it be like
our cloud of players things happen that
they're not there or the offer is just
so amazing we just
>> Yeah, it'd be either or. It'd be,
>> you know, the scenarios would be, okay,
we're at pick eight and we've got four
guys that we love and so we could go
back to as far as 12. Um, if there's two
that we love, then we could only go
back, you know, two spots, right?
or someone comes in and says, "We'll
give you three first round picks to
move." You know, yeah,
may have to do that, right? So, it's
either or. Um,
but I'm not someone that just wants to
trade just to have a transaction, you
know? I
u it's got to be really specific as to
what we're getting.
How much does
>> and some and some of that by the way
comes into play about who are you
trading with and what's their likelihood
that that pick is going to be late the
next year versus earlier and so all that
comes into play um when we're you know
making that assessment
>> you know that's what I was going to
follow up with how much do the say trade
terms
change from year to year in other words
hypothetically you were going to trade
up to number three this Mhm.
>> Do you look at past years and what that
cost or could it change every year
according to what the draft is?
>> That's a good question. I think history
is is a really valuable tool for us,
right? So, we've got the history of
trades and you know, I pour over that.
We have guys that pour over it. Um, and
then we have these point charts, right?
which I think the good thing is is uh
almost all the teams use these point
charts now to value at least that's the
starting point and if we're all on the
same point chart which we all always
aren't um
that's the starting point and then you
look at hey what historically has it
taken and then it becomes a matter of
market right some years there's a lot of
teams that want to move back and not
very many want to move up and so um
that's an advantage for the team moving
up because you know the markets uh
dictates a better a better cost.
>> Mickey, you said sometimes you consider
if you're trading with another team for
a future pick where you think they're
going to be drafting next year. If you
trade
>> your pick next year, what what what pick
will that be
>> in your mind?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. You're not
going to trap me on that one.
>> Are you
>> 32? I think it's going to be pick 32.
>> You say you're going to trade with
trading pick 32.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm going with. Does
when you talking about being risk
adverse earlier, does that like change
how you feel about potentially trading
into the top five? You know, that that
cost to get a premium type of pick.
>> Um,
no. I mean, if you're trading in pick
five, you know, that's you're not
looking for risk, you're looking for the
sure thing, right? So, I guess in that
sense, yeah, maybe a little bit, but,
you know, I like the spot we're in. I
know we're going to get a good player.
Um, so I I can't really answer that
though.
>> Was it Was it Dion Jordan that year that
that trade up? Actually, that was Jeff.
Like, was that the cheapest it's ever
been to? Was that year an extreme
outlier or have there been others where
>> um
Well, you know, it's funny. We've talked
about this a little bit because when I
was in Seattle, you know, Randy, um, we
had pick 10 and 11 and we ended up with
pick three and six and the cost for that
those total moves were um, really good
relative to today's prices. Um, and you
know, we ended up drafting Sean Springs
and Walter Jones with those two picks
and that was pretty good deal.
>> Um, really good deal,
>> has it?
>> But that, you know, it's different now.
um think you know the cost is higher
generally speaking.
>> Has that risk averse philosophy changed
over the years based on like players
that may or may not have worked out or
is it as you were saying earlier more
based on like picking
>> Yeah. I
>> higher or lower.
>> I think we're always affected by you
know what we've done in the past and
>> I got a long past so yeah I think we're
we're yeah it definitely affects you.
you know, we relate to, you know, a lot
of what we do is comparison, right? This
player compared to that player, this
deal compared to, you know, a deal that
we've done in the past. And so, um,
those ones that didn't work out
definitely affect, you know, our
thinking to some degree.
>> Can you just talking about that a little
bit when you talk about your history?
I'm sure there's been years here where
when you know you had Drew in his prime,
it's like step on the gas and go all in
now. Yeah. versus maybe where you are
right now in kind of balancing being
aggressive versus being patient.
>> Yeah. Um is there a question there?
>> Yeah, I guess what is your philosophy on
that? You know, having done for a long
time, maybe where are you right now in
and how is it hard to be patient knowing
that you may not not to say I know you
said you weren't pick 32, but knowing
that where you are right now?
>> Well, I I would say it this way when you
have a Drew Brees, right? when you have
that type that caliber of quarterback,
you're always feeling like you're one
player away, right? And so, man, let's
go get the one player. Um, and when you
have a young quarterback and you're
developing your roster, then you're not
one player away. So, you're less
inclined to give up, you know, a number
of assets uh to get, you know, one
player. Uh, that's probably the best way
I can describe it.
>> Well, where where are you guys though? I
mean, after the success you had late
last year, we're not one We're not one
player away.
>> Are you are But when you were just
describing that, I mean,
>> are you closer to pushing the gas after
the way last season ended or or not
necessarily?
>> Yeah, I I mean I wouldn't say I mean
that that's a five game stretch, right?
Or six game stretch. So
>> I don't want to read too much into that.
We're excited. We're optimistic um about
our future, but we're not
by no means have we arrived anywhere.
We have time for two or three more.
>> Mickey, uh I I don't know I don't know
if you thought a lot about this at all,
but like with NIL with the COVID uh year
and the some players coming out after
six, seven years in college, 25 year old
prospects. Has that like changed um how
you're having to evaluate some of these
guys where maybe it's a little bit
different than it was 10 years ago with
>> Yeah, I I think it's a double-edged
sword, right? Um because and we're
talking about the age of the players.
>> Yep.
On the one hand, look, there's probably
less opportunity for, you know, a big
development with the the older player.
On the other hand, we've got a lot more
information and we can do a better job
evaluating. And so, I don't necessarily
think it's a good or bad thing. Um, I I
just think it's something we're going to
have to deal with, you know, these guys.
And I look I think overall it's a good
thing that they stay in college and
develop um and they have the opportunity
to um you know one of the things about
the NIL is these guys their earning
years have expanded right because it's
not just earning it doesn't just happen
in the pros it happens in in college too
and that's a good thing for for these
guys. So um it's just something we have
to deal with and and I think we've done
a good job of that. But you know the
positive thing is we get more
information.
What are the things that make you or
make an NFL team remove a player from a
board or want to avoid a player from a
risk perspective?
>> Oh man, that it can be a lot of things
really. It can be have to do with, you
know,
practice habits or character. It can
happen, you know, injury, uh, uh,
history.
I mean, there's just so many things and
maybe just the fit of the player. You
know, there may be a player that doesn't
fit in our particular scheme and as good
as we think he is, he just doesn't fit
for what we're trying to get
accomplished. So, it can be a lot of
things. Uh it's not it's never just one
thing. Last one.
>> Um, is that dynamic kickoff rule? Is
that add like a a different element to
like especially day three for guys who
maybe are like a one skill set type of
player in like like would you be able to
get like a heat or whatever and in
>> as a priority free agent versus you know
now?
>> Yeah, I I think that's more dependent
upon what your roster looks like. But
look, we have to, you know, we pay
attention to special teams and and uh
and the kickoff rule changes have
affected a little bit the makeup of of
your your roster in that regard. And so
there there's I wouldn't say it's a big
deal, but it is, you know, it is a um it
is variable.